Thomas Tingey Craven Papers
Thomas Tingey Craven Papers
1841-1869
Craven, Thomas, 1808-1887.
1 linear ft.
Papers of the American admiral and Office of the Budget official. Correspondence, journal, miscellanea.
2642898
Biographical History
Thomas Tingey Craven (1808-1887) was an American Civil War admiral and instructor at the U.S. Naval Academy at Annapolis.
Craven was born December 20, 1808 in the District of Columbia. His father, Tunis Craven, who was a native of New Jersey and who early in life was a merchant in Alexandria, Virginia, was a purser in the navy, 1812-1813, and for many years a naval storekeeper, first at Portsmouth, N. H., and later at Brooklyn, N. Y. His mother, Hannah(Tingey) Craven, was a daughter of Commodore Thomas Tingey.
Entering the navy as a midshipman from New Hampshire on May 1, 1822, Craven was made a passed midshipman in 1828, and a lieutenant in 1830. In the last-named grade, he served off the Brazilian coast and in East Indian waters, and later, in 1838-1839, as first lieutenant of the Vincennes, the flagship of the Wilkes exploring expedition. In 1843-1844 he assisted Commodore M. C. Perry in suppressing the slave-trade off the coast of Africa, part of the time as commander of the schooner Porpoise. For almost eight years (1850-1855 and 1858-1860) he was commandant of midshipmen at the Naval Academy. He initiated and elaborated the practise cruise, still regarded as one of the most beneficial features of the course at Annapolis. In 1852 he was promoted commander and in the first year of the Civil War while in command of the Potomac flotilla, he was made a captain. In the following year he commanded the Brooklyn of Farragut's squadron on the Mississippi and had an active share in the stirring events that resulted in the opening of that river.
In 1863 he was made a commodore and was ordered with the steam frigate Niagara to European waters there to perform certain special duties, which included the protection of American commerce. In August 1864 he captured the Confederate steamer Georgia off the coast of Portugal. Eight months later off the coast of Spain near Corunna, the commander of the Confederate ironclad ram Stonewall challenged Craven to a trial of strength in the open sea. In addition to the Niagara the Commodore at this time had under his control the sloop-of-war Sacramento These two wooden ships carried an armament superior in the number of guns, but otherwise much inferior to that of the Stonewall. Craven therefore declined the challenge and allowed the Stonewall to proceed on her way unmolested. His action was much criticized and on his return to the United States he was brought before a court martial composed of nine of the most distinguished officers of the navy, with Vice-Admiral Farragut as president. The court found him guilty of failing to do his utmost to destroy the Stonewall and sentenced him to be suspended from duty for two years on leave-pay. On the ground that the finding was inconsistent, Secretary Gideon Welles set aside the proceedings of the court and discharged Craven from arrest. The Secretary, nevertheless, was of the opinion that the Commodore was too cautious an officer (Diary of Gideon Welles, vol. II, 1911, p. 267).
In 1866 Craven was promoted rear admiral, and, after serving as commandant of the Mare Island navy-yard and commander of the Pacific Squadron, he retired in 1869. The following year he served as port admiral at San Francisco. He died at the Boston navy-yard.
Craven's first wife was his cousin, Virginia Wingate; his second, Emily Truxton Henderson, by whom he had eight children. Three of his sons graduated from the Naval Academy.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Thomas Tingey Craven Papers contains correspondence, a journal, and some miscellanea.
The correspondence consists of letterbooks which have been disbound. Letterbook "A" covers 1841 to 1854 and includes letters and orders, many of which are copies of originals, and copies of sworn testimony. This material relates to the period in which Craven commanded the Porpoise in the African Squadron and contains many letters and orders signed by Matthew C. Perry, the commander of the squadron. It also includes material relating to Craven's service as commandant of midshipmen at the Naval Academy, particularly the practice cruises made by the midshipmen. Much of the material is of a routine nature, but there are some items of special interest: for example, letters, orders, and sworn testimony relating to the murder of the first mate on the brig Uncas, an alleged slave ship captured by the Porpoise in African waters; letters dealing with an incident in which some prisoners were allowed to escape from an officer because of the intervention of a crowd; letters involving payment for musical instruments purchased by Craven while serving at Buffalo, New York; and letters relating to the outfitting, sailing, and administration of the ship used for the practice cruises of the midshipmen.
Letterbook "B" covers 1861 to 1865. Included are letters and orders, many of which are copies of originals and some of which are written in Spanish and French, and copies of diplomatic dispatches. Much of the material is of a routine nature. The correspondence from 1861 was entered at the back of the letterbook and deals with activity on the Potomac at the beginning of the Civil War, when Craven commanded the Potomac Squadron. The bulk of the letterbook deals with the years 1864 and 1865 when Craven commanded the steamer Niagara in European waters, with the majority being letters by diplomatic personnel in Europe relating to such matters as release of British subjects or Portuguese subjects from service in the American navy, the movement of privateers, and relations with the French government and the Spanish government, particularly in regard to the use of the ports of those nations for the equipping of Confederate ships. Most notable among the latter are a series of letters, orders, telegrams, and diplomatic reports which relate to the outfitting of the Confederate ironclad ram Stonewall in a Spanish port.
Craven was responsible for containing her activities and attempting her destruction, for which task he had the assistance of the Sacramento. A telegram from Vice-Admiral Farragut ordering him back to the United States to stand trial for his failure to carry out his responsibility can be found here. The letterbook includes correspondence of Charles Francis Adams (1807-1886), American ambassador to Britain; Gideon Welles, Secretary of the Navy; David G. Farragut,; Henry Walke, commander of the Sacramento; and W. C. Dayton, an American diplomat in Paris, as well as several other diplomats (Horatio J. Perry in Madrid, James F. Harvey in Lisbon, Benjamin Mason in London, and James S. Pike in Amsterdam)
Arrangement of the Collection
Correspondence is arranged roughly chronologically, in the order which Craven had it in his letterbooks. An index to correspondence, and an index to General Orders and other military communications, appear at the end of this inventory.
Subject and Genre Headings
Military history; Civil War (U.S.); Adams, Charles Francis, 1807-1886.; Craven, Thomas, 1808-1887.; Farragut, David Glasgow, 1801-1870.; Perry, Matthew Calbraith, 1794-1858.; Walke, Henry, 1808-1896.; Welles, Gideon, 1802-1878.; Niagara (Steam frigate); Porpoise (Schooner); United States. -- Navy. -- Officers.; United States Naval Academy; United States History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Naval operations.; Correspondence.; Diaries.; Orders (military records); Telegrams.; Testimonies.; Admirals.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Purchase, various.
Inventory
- Correspondence
  - 1841-1844, 3 folders (Box 1)
  - 1846-1854, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - 1861 (Box 1)
  - 1863-1865, 11 folders (Box 1)
  - 1866-1869, 7 folders (Box 2)
- Writings
  - Journal, 19 Jun 1855; cruise in the U.S.S. Congress, T. T. Craven Esq. Commander, New York Navy Yard; 161 pp. (Box 2)
- Miscellanea
  - Depositions and affidavits, with covering letter, in the matter of chiefmate Joseph M. Richardson, charged in the murder of Robert G. Standon on the brig Uncas, December 31, 1843., 1844 (Box 2)
    See also Correspondence: 1841-1844; correspondence relating to the murder is filed in 1844.
  - Regulations and rules (Box 2)
  - Other documents (Box 2)
Index to correspondence
Abbott, Joel 1844 Mar 13, USS Decatur, Cape Palmas 1844 Apr 25, USS Decatur, Porto Praya, Isl'd of St. Tago, to Francisco de Paula Bastez (copy)
Adams, Charles Francis 1864 Jul 8, London, to Legation of the United States 1864 Jul 23, Legation of U.S., London 1864 Jul 27, Legation of U.S., London 1864 Jul 27, Legation of U.S., London 1864 Jul 27, Legation of U.S., London 1864 Aug 18, Legation of U.S., London 1864 Aug 18, Legation of U.S., London (copy) 1864 Aug 26, Legation of U.S., London 1864 Sep 3, Legation of U.S., London (with 4 enclosures) 1864 Oct 31, Legation of U.S., London 1864 Dec 24, Legation of U.S., London
Alden, James 1868 Oct 13, Vallejo, Calif. (telegram) 1869 May 14, Washington (telegram) 1869 May 14, Washington (telegram) 1869 May 18, Navy Dept., Washington 1869 Oct 5, Navy Dept., Washington 1869 Dec 7, Navy Dept., Washington
Anderson, A. W. 1844 Jun 15, Monrovia, West Africa, to Matthew C. Perry
Archer, Pierce, Jr. 1864 May 1, Philadelphia, to Hiram Paulding
Bancroft, George 1846 Feb 19, Navy Dept., (Washington)
Beckwith, N.M. 1864 Jun 30, Paris
Bell, Charles A. 1866 Nov 30, Navy Yard, N.Y.
Benedict, Sramueli 1844 Jul 17, Government Office, Monrovia, West Africa (plus a copy)
Benjamin, E.M. 1867 May 14, Navy Yard, Mare Island, to J.C. Hoffmann (a recommendation on a printed form)
Berry, Francis 1864 May 1, USS Niagara, to "Mother and Brother" (copy) 1864 May 28, USS Niagara, to Lord Palmerston (copy) (enclosed with Charles Frances Adams to TTC, 1864, Jul 27) 1864 Aug 3, USS Niagara, Liverpool, England, to "Mother" (copy) (enclosed with Charles Francis Adams to TTC, 1864, Sep 3)
Berthemy (?) 1868 Mar 16, Washington, to Secretary of State
Bigelow, George A. 1864 Sep 3, USS Niagara, Flushing
Bigelow, John 1865 Feb 8, Paris, to Horatio J. Perry (copy) 1865 Feb 28, Paris, to "Commodore"
Bilbado, Rafael 1865 Mar 24, Madrid, to "Commodore"
Black (?), Eugene 1864 Mar 30, USS Niagara at Sea
Borie, Adolph E. 1869 Mar 15, Washington (telegram) 1869 Mar 17, Navy Dept., Washington 1869 Mar 17, Navy Dept., Washington 1869 Apr 13, Navy Dept., Washington 1869 Jun 7, Navy Dept., Washington (telegram)
Bridge, H. 1844 Mar 4, USS Saratoga, to R. Pettit
Brightman, Henry A. 1844 Sep 30, US Brig Mattapoisett, Porto Grande, Island of St. Vincent, to Matthew C. Perry (copy) (enclosed are 5 items, copies of depositions by the Mattapoisett crew on charges against Isaac Dudley for threatening the life of Henry A. Brightman)
Cassell, Alexander W. 1864 Mar 29, USS Niagara at Sea, to Henry Erben, Jr.
Champlin, Stephen 1846 Sep 29, USS Michigan, Erie, Pa.
Chapman, G.W. (w/George Maulsby and Robert Pettit) 1844 Mar 2, US Brig Porpoise at anchor off the Galinas River, W. Coast Africa (plus a copy) 1844 Mar 4, Brigantine Uncas, Mesurado Roads (copy)
Clark, Samuel B. 1864 Mar 10, USS Niagara, New York 1867 Dec 5, Geneva
Conness, John 1867 May 15, San Francisco 1867 Jun 4, Georgetown
Conrad, Charles Magill 1851 Jul 18, Navy Dept., Washington, to C.K. Stibling (copy) 1851 Jul 29, Navy Dept., Washington 1851 Oct 10, Navy Dept., Washington
Craven, Alfred 1868 Oct 15, Vallejo, California (telegram)
Craven, Thomas T. 1844 Mar 7, US Brig Porpoise, Cape Mesurado, to Josiah Tattnall (copy) 1844 Jun 1, US Brig Porpoise Meduru, West Coast, Africa, to E.C. Ward 1844 Jun 3, US Brig Porpoise, to George M. Dibble (copy) (inside Dibble to Craven, same date) 1851 Oct 1, US Practice Ship, Preble, Annapolis, Maryland, to C.K. Stibling (copy) 1864 Jan 1, USS Niagara, to Hiram Paulding 1864 Aug 15, USS Niagara, off coast of Portugal, to Jacob Kimball 1865 Feb 12, Coruna, Spain, to Horatio J. Perry (telegram) 1865 Feb 13, Coruna, Spain, to Horatio J. Perry (telegram)
Crawford, A. N. 1864 Sep 22, Antwerp, Belgium (telegram) 1864 Oct 11, Antwerp, Belgium, to Benjamin Moran (copy) 1864 Oct 14, Antwerp, Belgium 1864 Oct 25, Antwerp, Belgium (telegram) 1864 Dec 29, Antwerp, Belgium, to [James] Hector (telegram) 1864 Dec 31, Antwerp, Belgium (telegram)
Cunha Pereira de Sotto Maior, A.M. da see Sotomaior
Dahlgren, John A.B. 1868 Aug 20, Navy Dept., Washington D. C. 1868 Nov 12, Navy Dept., Washington D. C.
Dainese, F. 1864 Jul 20, Alexandria, Egypt, to Capt. Stellwagen (enclosed with his letter of 1864 Jul 27) 1864 Jul 27, Alexandria, Egypt, to Commander of US Squadron in Mediterranean
Darnall, James M. 1868 Oct 27, Washington Navy Yard, to [Gideon Welles]
Day, J. Lawrence 1844 Jan 17, West Africa
Day, John 1844 Jul 12, ?Benley, to [ ]
Dayton, William Lewis 1864 Jul 15, Legation of US, Paris (telegram) 1864 Jul 27, Legation of US, Paris, to John A. Winslow 1864 Jul 27, Legation of US, Paris 1864 Aug 4, Legation of US, Paris 1864 Aug 29, Legation of US, Paris 1864 Sep 23, Legation of US, Paris 1864 Oct 13, Legation of US, Paris 1864 Nov 7, Legation of US, Paris
Denio (?), C.B. 1867 Jun 3, Mare Island, California, to J.D. Hoffman (a recommendation on a printed form) 1869 Jun 23, Vallejo, California, to John A. Rawlins
Dibble, George M. 1844 Jun 3, US Brig Porpoise, at Sea 1844 Jun 3, US Brig Porpoise, at Sea
Dobbin, James Cochran 1854 Jun 9, Navy Dept., Washington D. C., to Louis M. Goldsborough
Doran, Edward C. 1866 Nov 30, San Francisco 1868 Jun 15, San Francisco 1869 Apr 22, San Francisco 1869 Oct 9, San Francisco
Downes, John 1851 Sep 9, Boston, Massachusetts
Downs, H. P. 1869 May 20, Sacramento, California, to G. W. Rollins (copy)
Dudley, Isaac see Brightman, Henry A.
Dudley, Thomas H. 1864 Jul 10, Liverpool, England, to Benjamin Moran 1864 Aug 11, Liverpool, England, to American Consul in Lisbon (telegram) 1864 Oct 11, Liverpool, England, printed circular on the new screw steamer Laurel 1864 Nov 5, Liverpool, England 1864 Nov 10, Liverpool, England 1864 Nov 13, Liverpool, England 1864 Dec 26, Liverpool, England 1864 Dec 28, Liverpool, England (telegram) 1864 Dec 29, Liverpool, England (telegram) 1865 Mar 3, Liverpool, England, to Horatio J. Perry 1865 Mar ? 18, Liverpool, England (telegram) 1865 Mar 19, Liverpool, England, to James E. Harvey 1865 Mar 21, Liverpool, England, to James E. Harvey
Dulles, Joseph H. 1868 Jun 25, Office of the Triunfo Mining Co., Philadelphia, to [ ]
Eastman, Edwin G. 1864 Jul 18, U. S. Consulate, Cork, to Charles Francis Adams (copy inside Winslow to Craven, 1864 Jul 21)
Eldridge, Oliver 1867 Jan 31, San Francisco, Capt. McDougal and Edward C. Doran
Farragut, David Glasgow 1869 Aug 6, Vallejo, California
Faxon, William 1868 Aug 6, Washington (telegram) 1868 Aug 14, Washington (telegram) 1868 Aug 14, Washington
Fernandez, Alonso T. 1865 --, [Ferrol?] 1865 Feb 15, Ferrol 1865 Feb 18, Ferrol 1865 Feb 20, Ferrol 1865 Feb 21, Ferrol 1865 Feb 26, Ferrol 1865 Mar 6, Ferrol 1865 Mar 20, Ferrol 1865 Mar 21, Ferrol (telegram) 1865 Mar 21, Ferrol 1865 Mar 24, Ferrol, to [ ]
Fillebrown, Thomas S. 1868 Dec 3, Navy Dept., Washington D. C. 1869 Jan 6, Navy Dept., Washington D. C.
Fox, Henry 1865 May 19, Plymouth
Fox, Gustavus Vasa 1863 Sep 8, Navy Dept., Washington D. C., to Hiram Paulding 1864 Nov 29, Navy Dept., Washington D. C. 1865 Feb 25, Navy Dept., Washington D. C. 1865 Jun 3, Navy Dept., Washington D. C. 1865 Jun 5, Navy Dept., Washington D. C.
Fuertes, J 1865 Jul 4, [n.p.]
Gardner, F. 1844 May 3, Port Praya, West Africa
Goldsborough, Louis M. 1865 Jul 19, US Flag Ship Colorado, Flushing, Holland 1865 Jul 20, US Flag Ship Colorado, Flushing, Holland 1865 Jul 21, US Flag Ship Colorado, Flushing, Holland 1865 Jul 23, US Flag Ship Colorado, Flushing, Holland 1865 Jul 23, US Flag Ship Colorado, Flushing, Holland
Goodrich, Aaron 1864 Oct 1, Brussels
Graham, William Alexander 1850 Aug 6, Navy Dept., Washington D. C., to O.S.K. Peck 1852 Jun 10, Navy Dept., Washington D. C., to C. K. Stribling (copy)
Green, J. F. 1865 Sep 22, Navy Yard, Boston
Greene, B. F. 1864 Dec 7, Navy Dept., Washington D. C. (on a printed circular)
Greene, Samuel Dana 1869 Apr 22, Mare Island, California, to L. C. Sartori
Hamilton, Philip 1864 Mar 7, Brooklyn, New York
Harvey, James E. 1864 ca. Aug, Portugal 1864 Aug 12, Portugal 1865 Mar 5, Lisbon, Portugal 1865 Mar 29, Lisbon, Portugal, to duque de Loule [Nuno José Severo de Mendoça Rolim de Mourá Barreto] 1865 Mar 31, Lisbon, Portugal 1865 Apr 6, Lisbon, Portugal, to duque de Loule [Nuno José Severo de Mendoça Rolim de Mourá Barreto] 1865 Apr 8, Lisbon, Portugal 1865 Nov 15, Lisbon, Portugal
Hector, James 1864 Sep 10?, (telegram)
Jenkins, Thornton Alexander 1868 Jul 18, Navy Dept., Washington D. C. 1868 Sep 5, Navy Dept., Washington D. C. 1868 Sep 9, Navy Dept., Washington D. C. 1868 Sep 14, Navy Dept., Washington D. C. 1868 Sep 18, Navy Dept., Washington D. C. 1868 Sep 21, Navy Dept., Washington D. C. (telegram) 1868 Sep 22, Navy Dept., Washington D. C. 1868 Oct 2, Navy Dept., Washingtion D. C. (telegram) 1868 Oct 5, Navy Dept., Washington D. C. (telegram) 1868 Oct 14, Navy Dept., Washington D. C. (copy) 1868 Oct 14, Navy Dept., Washington D. C. 1868 Oct 14, Navy Dept., Washington D. C. 1868 Oct 14, Navy Dept., Washington D. C. 1868 Oct 16, Navy Dept., Washington D. C. 1868 Oct 28, Navy Dept., Washington D. C. 1868 Nov 30, Navy Dept., Washington D. C. 1868 Dec 2, Navy Dept., Washington D. C. 1868 Dec 2, Navy Dept., Washington D. C. 1868 Dec 19, Navy Dept., Washington D. C. 1869 Jan 1, Navy Dept., Washington D. C. 1869 Jan 7, Navy Dept., Washington D. C. 1869 Jan 15, Navy Dept., Washington D. C. 1869 Jan 16, Navy Dept., Washington D. C. 1869 Jan 22, Navy Dept., Washington D. C. 1869 Feb 13, Navy Dept., Washington D. C. 1869 Feb 17, Navy Dept., Washington D. C.
Johnson, George C. 1868 Jun 3?, San Francisco 1868 Jun 18?, San Francisco
Kennedy, John Pendleton 1853 Jan 28, Washington D. C.
Kimball, Jacob 1864 Oct 8, Salem
Kitchen, John S. 1864 Aug 31, Flushing, to Henry Walke
Labado, H.? 1865 Jan 27, Palais Belle-Ile, to Pierre Sisco (with Sisco to Craven, 1865 Jan 31)
Lenthall, John 1868 Jan 6, Navy Dept., Washington D. C. (copy) 1868 Nov 21, Navy Dept., Washington, to Gideon Welles (copy)
Lewis, Robert R. 1869 Apr 8, USS Resaca 1869 Apr 18, USS Resaca, San Francisco
Lockwood, Henry H. 1851 Oct 12, Annapolis, Maryland
Loule, duque de [Nuno José Severo de Mendoça Rolim de Mourá Barreto] 1865 Mar 31, Lisbon, to James E. Harvey
Luce, Stephen Bleecker 1869 Mar 6, Mare Island, California
Ludlow (?), A. 1864 May 26, Navy Yard, New York
McCulloch, Hugh 1869 Jan 28, Treasury Department (copy), to Gideon Welles 1869 Jan 30, Treasury Department (copy), to Gideon Welles
Mason, John Young 1844 Dec 2, Navy Department, Washington D. C. 1844 Dec 6, Navy Department, Washington D. C. 1847 Mar 25, Navy Department, Washington D. C. 1844 Apr 9, Navy Department, Washington D. C.
Maulsby, George see Chapman, G. W.
Mayo, J. 1844 Oct 22, US Macedonian, Porto Praya, West Africa, to Matthew C. Perry
Meade, Richard Worsam 1864 Feb 24, USS North Carolina, to Hiram Paulding 1869 Apr 3, Victoria (telegram) 1869 Apr 5, Victoria (telegram)
Millet (?), H. J. 1864 May 27, [New York]
Milliken, C. A. 1846 Sep 19, Buffalo, N. Y.
Missroon (?), J. S. 1863 Oct 15, Navy Yard, Boston 1863 Oct 17, Navy Yard, Boston 1863 Oct 17, Navy Yard, Boston, to John B. Montgomery 1863 Oct --, Navy Yard, Boston, to Henry A. Wise 1863 Oct --, Navy Yard, Boston
Mitchell, John G. 1868 Aug 14, Victoria (telegram) 1868 Aug 18, San Francisco (telegram) 1868 Aug 19, San Francisco, to Paul Shirley (telegram) 1868 Sep 16, San Francisco (telegram)
Montgomery, John Berrien 1863 Oct 15, Navy Yard, Boston 1863 Oct 17, Navy Yard, Boston 1863 Oct 17, Navy Yard, Boston 1863 Oct 21, Navy Yard, Boston 1863 Nov 5, Navy Yard, Boston
Moran, Benjamin 1864 Jul 20, London, to Henry Walke 1864 Jul 27, London, to John A. Winslow 1864 Aug 4, London, to H. Wilding (copy) 1864 Aug 25, London 1864 Aug 27, London 1864 Oct 11, London 1864 Oct 11, London, to Capt. Henry Walke (telegram) 1864 Oct 12, London, to Pierre Sisco (telegram) 1864 Oct 13, London 1864 Oct 21, London 1864 Oct 31, London 1865 Feb 24, London 1865 Mar 9, London 1865 Mar 18, London 1865 Jun 10, London, to Robert Warner
Moran, William P. 1863, Navy Department
Morris, Ann 1864 Aug 10, Bolton, to Lord Palmerston (copy) (petition, enclosed in Charles Francis Adams to TTC, 1864 Sep 3)
Morse, Freeman Harlow 1864 Aug 31, London 1864 Sep 3, London 1864 Sep 7, London 1864 Sep 10, London 1864 Oct 3, London 1864 Oct 11, London 1864 Oct 29, London 1864 Oct 30, London 1864 Nov 2, London 1864 Nov 2, London 1864 Nov 2, London (copy) (enclosed in Henry Walke to TTC, 1864 Nov 7) 1864 Nov 3, London, to [Henry] Walke 1864 Nov 29, London 1865 Jan 2, London (on verso of Vendroux letter of 1864 Dec 29)
Munro, C. A. 1864 Aug 13, Lisbon, to U. S. Consulate [n.p.] 1865 Mar 28, Lisbon
Nager, W. 1864 Mar 30, USS Niagara, to [ ]
Parnell, George 1869 Jan 16, Treasury Department, Washington, to W. C. S. Smith (copy)
Patten, William 1867 Jun 6, Mare Island, California 1867 Jun 7, Mare Island, California 1867 Jun 7, Mare Island, California 1867 Jun 10, Mare Island, California
Paulding, Hiram 1863 Jan 2, Navy Yard, New York 1863 Dec 25, Navy Yard, New York 1863 Dec 29, Navy Yard, New York 1864 Jan 1, Navy Yard, New York 1864 Jan 2, Navy Yard, New York 1864 Jan 4, Navy Yard, New York, to [James Shedden] Palmer 1864 Jan 4, Navy Yard, New York 1864 Jan 10, Navy Yard, New York 1864 Jan 11, Navy Yard, New York 1864 Jan 27, Navy Yard, New York 1864 Feb 4, Navy Yard, New York 1864 Feb 5, Navy Yard, New York 1864 Mar 3, Navy Yard, New York 1864 Apr 20, Navy Yard, New York 1864 May 2, Navy Yard, New York 1864 May 4, Navy Yard, New York 1864 May 12, Navy Yard, New York 1864 May 16, Navy Yard, New York 1864 May 23, Navy Yard, New York 1864 May 24, Navy Yard, New York 1864 May 25, Navy Yard, New York 1864 May 30, Navy Yard, New York
Peck, 0. S. K. 1850 Jul 18, Washington 1850 Aug 13, Washington
Pereira de Sotto Maior, A. M. da Cunha see Sotomaior
Perry, Horatio J. 1865 Feb 8, Madrid, Spain, to John Bigelow (copy) 1850 Feb 8, Madrid, Spain, to William H. Seward 1850 Feb 9, Madrid, Spain, to M. de Mercier (?) 1850 Feb 13, Madrid, Spain (telegram) 1850 Feb 13, Madrid, Spain, to William H. Seward 1850 Feb 16, Madrid, Spain 1850 Feb 23, Madrid, Spain 1850 ca. Mar 1850 Mar 4, Madrid, Spain 1850 Mar 5, Madrid, Spain 1850 Mar 6, Madrid, Spain 1850 Mar 7, Madrid, Spain 1850 Mar 18, Madrid, Spain (inside H. G. Wilding to Perry, 1865 Mar 14) 1850 Mar 22, Madrid, Spain 1850 Mar 23, Madrid, Spain 1850 Mar 24, Madrid, Spain, to